<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Cino</title><link>https://cino.io/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Cino</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cino.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Avoiding CloudFormation Stack Outputs</title><link>https://cino.io/2024/avoid-cloudformation-stack-outputs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cino.io/2024/avoid-cloudformation-stack-outputs/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a new project where we created many resources in a lot of different stacks. A feature of CloudFormation is that you can output values from your stack, which is great for referencing resources in other stacks. However, while there is a use-case for this, I&amp;rsquo;ve found that it&amp;rsquo;s better to avoid using these outputs and instead use SSM parameters.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TIL #2 - Multiple ways to retrieve SSM parameters in AWS CDK</title><link>https://cino.io/2024/multiple-ways-to-retrieve-ssm-parameters-cdk/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cino.io/2024/multiple-ways-to-retrieve-ssm-parameters-cdk/</guid><description>&lt;p>When working with AWS CDK and using SSM Parameters to store information in between stacks there are multiple ways to retrieve the value, with both advantages and disadvantages. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll go over the different ways to retrieve SSM parameters in AWS CDK and when to use them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AWS Parameter Store vs AWS Secrets</title><link>https://cino.io/2023/aws-parameter-store-vs-aws-secrets/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cino.io/2023/aws-parameter-store-vs-aws-secrets/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been using AWS Secrets to retrieve API keys which are needed to access external API&amp;rsquo;s, however, this turned out to be a more expensive service than we initially thought when starting.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using password(les)s in 2023</title><link>https://cino.io/2023/using-passwords-in-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cino.io/2023/using-passwords-in-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been almost a year since I&amp;rsquo;ve started using my YubiKey, even though I only recently bought a backup key (yes, you can shame me) I decided it is time to have big write up on why you should be using a hardware key with Fido2(WebAuthn) support too.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AWS Learning badge assignments</title><link>https://cino.io/2023/aws-learning-badge-assignments/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cino.io/2023/aws-learning-badge-assignments/</guid><description>&lt;p>Besides the AWS Certification program, there are also the newer AWS Learning skill badges. A new-ish way of learning the skills necessary to work on the aws platform and illustrate your knowledge. These are like the certifications except they are &lt;strong>not&lt;/strong> certifications of some kind and you can take exams to receive the &amp;ldquo;Skill badge&amp;rdquo;, this is all for free and is here to help you. I finished them all and wanted to highlight each of them, and how I experienced each of the exams.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Every repository should contain a DevContainer</title><link>https://cino.io/2023/every-repository-should-contain-a-devcontainer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cino.io/2023/every-repository-should-contain-a-devcontainer/</guid><description>&lt;p>Almost a year ago I visited an AWS User Group (Amsterdam) meetup where someone gave a presentation on using Microsoft &lt;a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/docs/devcontainers/containers">Dev Containers&lt;/a> in your projects. Even though I tried it before, this gave me the momentum to actually commit to it and have never looked back. And I want you to do the same.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Limiting AWS Lambda's access to Log Groups</title><link>https://cino.io/2022/limiting-aws-lambdas-access-to-log-groups/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cino.io/2022/limiting-aws-lambdas-access-to-log-groups/</guid><description>&lt;p>About a year ago I asked the question on &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/aws/comments/o3fbge/is_awslambdabasicexecutionrole_not_way_too_open/" target="_blank">Reddit&lt;/a> what people thought of the default Lambda role called &amp;ldquo;AWSLambdaBasicExecutionRole&amp;rdquo; and why I thought it was way too open to be a default.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To this day I still think this role shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be used at all, but rather be deleted by Amazon itself. While I agree that Amazon wants people to get started as quickly as possible it is not in line with the least access principle. For this reason, I always define the role myself, for starters only allowing the Lambda function to write to its own CloudWatch Log Group. There is no reason for the Lambda function to be able to write to log groups of other services rather than its own.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building a Serverless Kanban Board</title><link>https://cino.io/2022/building-a-serverless-kanban-board/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cino.io/2022/building-a-serverless-kanban-board/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update 18/01/2023: Let&amp;rsquo;s assume this is not gonna happen anymore&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As the title suggests I&amp;rsquo;m planning on building a Serverless Kanban Board to improve my personal Typescript skills in both the front and back end. Furthermore, the whole project will be set up while using Amazon Web Services (of course 😉)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I thought it would be fun to build something for practice and also have some personal projects on my GitHub page that display the latest techniques I&amp;rsquo;m working with and as a bonus get some material I can write about on the website!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TIL #1 - You can override basically anything in AWS CDK</title><link>https://cino.io/2022/you-can-override-basically-anything-in-aws-cdk/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cino.io/2022/you-can-override-basically-anything-in-aws-cdk/</guid><description>&lt;p>Unique as I am I decided to start writing short blog posts about recent discoveries that suddenly clicked inside my head. For the first one; I have been working a lot with AWS CDK recently and decided that I wanted to contribute back to the AWS-CDK source code.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Temporarily working on a Windows Laptop</title><link>https://cino.io/2022/temporarily-working-on-a-windows-laptop/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cino.io/2022/temporarily-working-on-a-windows-laptop/</guid><description>&lt;p>This has been quite the struggle, for the last 6 years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a Macbook Pro/Air (m1) and right now I&amp;rsquo;m not able to do so. Due to a recent job change, I&amp;rsquo;m working on a Windows laptop until the new Macbook is in. At first, I was really curious to work on Windows again! I&amp;rsquo;ve been talking Microsoft up anytime I spoke with somebody about the company, the recent acquiries, the change in direction, I really like where the company is going.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploying your static website with a Github Action</title><link>https://cino.io/2022/deploying-your-static-website/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cino.io/2022/deploying-your-static-website/</guid><description>&lt;p>Authenticate GitHub with OpenID Connect to deploy your CDK project to your AWS Organization&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After making an AWS CDK project one of the first thing you will realize is that you don&amp;rsquo;t want to keep running cdk deploy to update your production environment. This is a fine way of working when you modify your personal dev environment as it is a quick way of deploying but definitely not for your staging/production environments.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Static website distribution with AWS CloudFront</title><link>https://cino.io/2022/static-website-distribution-with-aws-cloudfront/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cino.io/2022/static-website-distribution-with-aws-cloudfront/</guid><description>&lt;p>Having only written about PHP and Servers in the past I am making the switch to Serverless. This has been a long-time wish for me and finally realized this in a personal but also professional environment. That being said, I plan on writing a lot of new content on the blog purely around setting up applications with a serverless mindset, built with AWS CDK (AWS Cloud Development Kit). I will include diagrams and/or flowcharts to explain what is happening and of course, include the source code in a public GitHub repository.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The bigger goal for me is to develop a proper application on nothing but serverless services from Amazon to train my skillset and also share the process that I went through.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Optimizing PHP-FPM</title><link>https://cino.io/2019/optimizing-php-fpm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cino.io/2019/optimizing-php-fpm/</guid><description>&lt;p>As mentioned in the previous post about &lt;a href="https://cino.io/2019/laravel-forge-setting-it-up-the-right-way/" target="_blank">laravel forge and setting it up the right way&lt;/a> there was going to be a separate post just about PHP-FPM and how to configure it correctly.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Laravel Forge: setting it up the right way</title><link>https://cino.io/2019/laravel-forge-setting-it-up-the-right-way/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cino.io/2019/laravel-forge-setting-it-up-the-right-way/</guid><description>&lt;p>For the last couple of years, I’ve been creating servers with Laravel Forge and normally I would advise against doing this (In favor of running containers or other load balanced tasks), but for the sake of giving advice to those who do want to do it, this is the first post I’ll spend time on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the record, I’ll be writing from an AWS perspective since this is the only provider I have extensive experience with on Laravel Forge but I’ll expect the others to work quite the same.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>First post again</title><link>https://cino.io/2019/first-post-again/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cino.io/2019/first-post-again/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ah, we are back! Once again, this will be the third try of starting and actually updating a personal blog. I’m not exactly sure what I wrote down the last time but I’m planning the same.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>