<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Private on Cino</title><link>https://cino.io/tags/private/</link><description>Recent content in Private on Cino</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 18:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cino.io/tags/private/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Private AppSync with custom dns</title><link>https://cino.io/2025/private-appsync-with-custom-dns/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 18:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://cino.io/2025/private-appsync-with-custom-dns/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In the last year I&amp;rsquo;ve been working a &lt;strong&gt;lot&lt;/strong&gt; with AppSync and I have to say it didn&amp;rsquo;t come without challenges. One of the biggest challenges was to create a private AppSync API with a custom domain. This is something that is not natively supported by AWS, but it is possible to achieve it using a combination of services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this is now possible for API Gateway, AppSync is a different beast. There is no native way to create a private AppSync API with a private custom domain. This is something that I had to figure out the hard way, and I want to share my findings with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This might become a bit of a long read, but if you are looking for a way to create a private AppSync API with a custom domain, you are in the right place. I will try to explain the steps I took to achieve this and the challenges I faced along the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Private API Gateway with DNS</title><link>https://cino.io/2024/private-api-gateway-with-dns/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cino.io/2024/private-api-gateway-with-dns/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/strong&gt; Ofcourse, after I finalized this article Amazon released native support for &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/apigateway/latest/developerguide/apigateway-private-custom-domains.html"&gt;Private DNS on API Gateways.
&lt;/a&gt;. Announced on the &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/compute/implementing-custom-domain-names-for-private-endpoints-with-amazon-api-gateway/"&gt;AWS Blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At PostNL we are building most of our applications with &lt;a href="https://medium.com/postnl-engineering/business-overview-f7c8d8ebee2c"&gt;Serverless&lt;/a&gt; in mind, let me rephrase that, we build all our applications within our own landing zone with Serverless only. There is no option to deploy any kind of EC2 and if you need containers you&amp;rsquo;d be running them on Fargate only.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>