<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Amazon Web Services on Cino</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/amazon-web-services/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Amazon Web Services on Cino</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/amazon-web-services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding CloudFormation Stack Outputs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2024/avoid-cloudformation-stack-outputs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2024/avoid-cloudformation-stack-outputs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a new project where we created many resources in a lot of different stacks. A feature of CloudFormation is that you can output values from your stack, which is great for referencing resources in other stacks. However, while there is a use-case for this, I&amp;rsquo;ve found that it&amp;rsquo;s better to avoid using these outputs and instead use SSM parameters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TIL #2 - Multiple ways to retrieve SSM parameters in AWS CDK</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2024/multiple-ways-to-retrieve-ssm-parameters-cdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2024/multiple-ways-to-retrieve-ssm-parameters-cdk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When working with AWS CDK and using SSM Parameters to store information in between stacks there are multiple ways to retrieve the value, with both advantages and disadvantages. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll go over the different ways to retrieve SSM parameters in AWS CDK and when to use them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS Parameter Store vs AWS Secrets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/aws-parameter-store-vs-aws-secrets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2023/aws-parameter-store-vs-aws-secrets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been using AWS Secrets to retrieve API keys which are needed to access external API&amp;rsquo;s, however, this turned out to be a more expensive service than we initially thought when starting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS Learning badge assignments</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/aws-learning-badge-assignments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2023/aws-learning-badge-assignments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Besides the AWS Certification program, there are also the newer AWS Learning skill badges. A new-ish way of learning the skills necessary to work on the aws platform and illustrate your knowledge. These are like the certifications except they are &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; certifications of some kind and you can take exams to receive the &amp;ldquo;Skill badge&amp;rdquo;, this is all for free and is here to help you. I finished them all and wanted to highlight each of them, and how I experienced each of the exams.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
