<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>php on Cino</title><link>https://cino.io/tags/php/</link><description>Recent content in php on Cino</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cino.io/tags/php/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Optimizing PHP-FPM</title><link>https://cino.io/posts/optimizing-php-fpm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cino.io/posts/optimizing-php-fpm/</guid><description>As mentioned in the previous post about laravel forge and setting it up the right way there was going to be a separate post just about PHP-FPM and how to configure it correctly.
What is FPM? PHP-FPM stands for “Fast Process Manager” and is mostly being used in combination with an Nginx webserver. If you look at the config of an Nginx webserver which is set up to be used with PHP-fpm you’ll find a proxy pass that points to the PHP-FPM socket, meaning that whenever a certain request lands in Nginx it will be sent towards the PHP-FPM socket.</description></item><item><title>Laravel Forge: setting it up the right way</title><link>https://cino.io/posts/laravel-forge-setting-it-up-the-right-way/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cino.io/posts/laravel-forge-setting-it-up-the-right-way/</guid><description>For the last couple of years, I’ve been creating servers with Laravel Forge and normally I would advise against doing this (In favor of running containers or other load balanced tasks), but for the sake of giving advice to those who do want to do it, this is the first post I’ll spend time on it.
For the record, I’ll be writing from an AWS perspective since this is the only provider I have extensive experience with on Laravel Forge but I’ll expect the others to work quite the same.</description></item></channel></rss>